hey everyone dorothy reitzman here today
what i'm going to be doing on my model
janae is a full install of eye tips
using five different blends
[Music]
so for this classic installation that
i'm going to be doing i'm sectioning off
the hair to make it easier to diagram
and map out i've sectioned off the front
two because i'm not going to get to
there until at least row three now that
i'm here in the back i'm going to be
starting at the nape working my way up
my first section is going to be
horizontal
now that i've sectioned her hair up she
is blonde and her hair is nice and
healthy so you are going to have some
flyaways from time to time you want to
be careful with these because as you're
doing an installation they could become
into the cylinders and create crosshairs
it can be very irritating so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to take my
flyaway strip right through here i've
clipped the hair up nice and neat so i'm
just going to take my flyaway strip you
put it at the bottom of your section
push it up and it makes it nice and
clean and takes those flyaways away with
my model janae she just got her color
done and it's very beautiful so what i
want to do is i want to emphasize that
so i'm going to be doing something
between an ombre and a balayage
something like a sombre so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to put light
down here on my first couple of rows
then i'm going to intertwine some darker
pieces and then i am going to end with
that light again to give her that soft
dimension but really brighten her up
down towards the bottom
[Applause]
now that i've started my install i do
want to give you a little tip that i did
with the dreamcatcher's hair it's 100
human hair and the quality is very very
strong and high so i actually prepped
the hair by purple shampooing it because
like i said she just got her hair done
so her toner is nice and fresh the hair
has been sitting in the bag for a little
while so i wanted to fluff it up with
the dreamcatcher hair once you shampoo
it it really gives it that body and that
volume that you're really looking for so
i prepped the hair by purple shampooing
it giving it a clean blow-dry so that it
mimics more what she has in her hair
right now
[Music]
i've now completed my first row so just
a couple of tips that i want to point
out you can already see that her hair is
melting in with those extensions
something to look at more during your
consultation but it's something to
realize through your application the
more cylinders and hairs that you can
fit in the bottom the more hair you're
going to need for the head so when doing
your consultation take a look down at
this nape section and try to gauge how
many cylinders you're going to be able
to fit inside of this one row because if
you can fit a lot of cylinders here
you're going to need more double almost
triple through the top up through here
rather than less and that could make or
break your application on how dense and
how full your hair looks
now the other thing i wanted to point
out is you want to double check and make
sure when your client pulls their hair
up that it's not going to be seen so
what you can do is gauge leaving one to
two fingers around the hairline and then
i'm going to grab her hair here and i'm
going to pull it straight up as if she's
going to pull it into a pony and you'll
notice
you cannot see any of those cylinders
they're completely hidden which means
you left enough space underneath to
cover that
as you're going forward
so now i'm going to continue up the head
[Music]
you'll notice with my second row it is
slightly different than my first row my
first row i took horizontal sections
that's going to help create that maximum
density with section number two i've
worked from behind the ear to behind the
ear and i'm now in a u-shape this is
going to help emphasize the natural
structure of the head
so as i'm installing some people are
afraid to crimp it too tight
this could be a factor depending on the
type of quality of hair that you're
working with
so with dream catchers
with dream catchers the tip of the
extension is rubberized or fancy word
polyurethane so what that means and why
that is important is because when i
stick the tip inside of the cylinder
here
and i break it down and i pinch it
right here
that eye tip is then going to fill the
entire cylinder and cushion the client's
hair not all individual extensions are
like this a lot of times they have more
of a hard coating or a plastic coating
so that when you crimp it tight it's
going to break down and it's also
harsher on the client's natural hair so
finding that good quality tip is really
going to be essential within your
application and really the longevity of
both your clients hair and how long you
can actually wear these extensions
[Music]
so now that i'm approaching my third row
depending on the situation or how many
bundles you need to fit into your
client's head you can alter your
sections just a little bit
so with my model janae here i've done
more of a deep u where i'm like more
scooping underneath that's going to
allow me to fit more hair inside of my
client's head if this was just a classic
install or i was just doing about four
bundles then i would just go with more a
softer you that's not as deep and
dramatic adding that deepness allows you
to add more hair in she's naturally got
that dense hair so we're probably going
to be going upwards of six bundles
[Music]
i'm about three quarters of the way
through my third row
i did want to point out in the back
you're doing that u shape to help
emphasize that natural flow of the hair
you also can put more cylinders more
hairs in the head
as i go and transition to the side here
you will notice that it is now
horizontal
the reason for this is the sides are
always weaker the main reason is because
it's lacking so much of a hairline
that's in the back
always also around the hairline it's
always going to be more of a fragile
type of hair just because of that
transition on the head so when i'm
working towards the front i'm working
with a horizontal always on the sides
here so horizontal on the side and then
i transition in the back
[Music]
do
i've now completed row three a couple of
tips that i want to point out is when
i'm working through my row here i am
putting everything side by side no
natural hair in between this is going to
build that maximum density as i'm
working up through the head once i get
to the top you'll see that i start to
space them out to allow that natural to
come through
but i just wanted to show you here
everything is laying right next to each
other it's slightly away from the scalp
you have enough room to give she could
throw her hair up if she wanted to it's
not going to harm her
horizontal on the side again that deep u
in the back
allowing me to add more space for my
next row and then continuing to the
other side
the last thing i do want to point out is
like i said i'm doing something called a
sombre which is a soft ombre in between
ombre and balayage so you will see that
i started to add a little bit of that
dimension into her hair through here i
started off with solid blonde and as i
work up i'm slowly introducing those
darker to mid colors
[Music]
so i've now completed row number four it
looks identical to row number three
because we're putting so many bundles in
her hair because she naturally has that
thick dense hair
so you'll see on the sides it's still
that horizontal and it's still u-shaped
in the back this is going to be the last
row that i do side-by-side with no
natural hair in between as i go to the
next row in the back i'll start to space
out my cylinders to allow that natural
to come through on the sides i will
always stay horizontal because i always
need that maximum density
[Music]
so i've now completed janae's full
install i wanted to point out on my last
row here my row number five she does
have a heavy side part on this side over
here so i have raised the section on
this side a little bit higher than it is
on the other side to help compensate for
that weight difference from her heavy
part to her not heavy part so on the
side here i'm still horizontal side by
side with no natural hair in between but
as i go back through here you'll notice
i have now spaced it out
my row number four it's one cylinder
space apart my row number five it's
almost two
leaving that space there to allow that
natural hair to come through
once i finish my application what i like
to do is i like to go back row by row
and just double check check my
sectioning
and my cylinders as you're going through
sometimes you can get tiresome so you
just want to go back through ensure that
everything is nice and tight so that
they don't have any fallout as they come
back
now that i'm finished with the install
i'm going to go ahead and do the haircut
when you're hair cutting with extensions
typically you want to use a feather
razor because it helps give you those
rough edges as you're going through it
because it's nice and perfect so it's
going to help mirror that client's
natural texture
so you will notice that my client here
my model has more of a horizontal line
so i am just going to carve out on this
top layer just to help it diffuse within
the extensions i'm going to do that last
because i'm going to create that
layering effect first within the
extensions see how it falls and then
only
cut the client's hair as much as you
absolutely need to
taking where her natural stops that's
where i'm going to start
softly feathering creating a face
framing effect
it helps that transition
from the natural to wherever you're
ending your extensions
[Music]
just creating that movement within her
extensions
so now i'm just going to take her top
layer of her hair
just above row number five
so what i'm doing now as i am noticing i
can still see her structured line so i'm
going to go to her in between on where
that line is appearing
and help carve out right in between
now you don't want to go on top with
your feather razor because all that's
going to do is create more layering and
shorten the client's hair and that's not
your intention your intention is to help
break up this weight line from them
either having dense hair or a structured
haircut so when working with the clients
natural you're going to work from that
underneath to only remove density not
linked
you can see how it just starts to
diffuse that line
and it starts to disappear within the
extensions
so what i'm doing now as i am noticing i
can still see her structured line so i'm
going to go to her in between on where
that line is appearing
and help carve out right in between
you have that nice perfect application
it's easy to section and get out of the
way
so i'm going to finish up her haircut
and then i'm going to get to styling
[Music]
hi i'm janae and i came to the dream
catchers studio today and i got some
extensions in i got six bundles of eye
tips and i used to do the clip-ins but i
switched today and it is way more
comfortable feels more natural i don't
even notice that they're in there and it
lasts longer so
definitely check it out
you